<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Houston on Welcome</title>
    <link>/tags/houston/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Houston on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/houston/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Children At Risk Data: Graduation Rates</title>
      <link>/blog/houston_school_rankings_2018_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/houston_school_rankings_2018_2/</guid>
      <description>Houston area school districts show a wide disparity in graduation rates, according to the Children At Risk 2018 School Rankings.
Among independent school districts, rural districts possess the lowest and highest graduation rates.
Hardin ISD graduated an estimated 69.6% of its students while Danbury ISD graduated an estimated 96.2%.
There is also a very clear correlation with the Children At Risk’s grade ranking and graduation rates.
Outside of a couple outliers in the B+ and A grade, schools receiving a grade of F show the widest disparity in graduation rates among the various grades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What The 2018 Children At Risk Data Reveals About Houston Area Schools</title>
      <link>/blog/houston_school_rankings_2018_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/houston_school_rankings_2018_1/</guid>
      <description>The 2018 Children At Risk data reveals a startlingly trend: the declining quality of Houston area school districts.
The 20 largest Houston area school districts enroll nearly 1 million students – representing 81% of all Houston area enrolled students.
Since 2015, only 3 of the 20 largest districts have shown signs of improvement. That is according to the Children At Risk’s C@R school grade – a measure of overall school quality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>