<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oil on Welcome</title>
    <link>/tags/oil/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oil on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/oil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada: A Major Oil Import Source For The US</title>
      <link>/blog/canada_a_major_import_source_for_the_us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/canada_a_major_import_source_for_the_us/</guid>
      <description>Last year, my exploration into US imports of Canadian oil revealed both Canada’s dominance and growth as an import source.
One year later, Canada remains the top source of US oil imports and is poised to continue to grow its market share.
Canadian oil makes up nearly a majority of US oil imports in 2018, at 47% of all imports.
In May 2018, the US imported 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is The United States Crashing OPEC&#39;s Deal?</title>
      <link>/blog/is_the_united_states_crashing_opecs_deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/is_the_united_states_crashing_opecs_deal/</guid>
      <description>In September 2016, OPEC announced it’s first production cut in 8 years.
Three months later, Russia, Mexico, Kazakhstan, and Oman announced they would agree in principle to OPEC’s decission and cut their own production.
The cuts have been effective: the December 2017 average price for a barrel of oil was $58. That’s the highest December average since 2014.
With the increase in price comes the incentive to increase production.
Companies within United States may have the most to gain, and they may have the most proven swing producer record, outside of OPEC nations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Oil Imports: A Tale of One Country</title>
      <link>/blog/us_oil_imports_a_tale_of_one_country/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/us_oil_imports_a_tale_of_one_country/</guid>
      <description>Three years ago oil prices were in the $90’s. They now move between the $40’s and $50’s.
US oil production was on the rise three years ago, and it continued to rise for one year after the initial price decline, reaching 9.4 million barrels per day (mbpd) in 2015.
In 2016, oil production dropped to 8.8 mbpd, and production through the first six months of 2017 has averaged nearly 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Refinery Imports From Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>/blog/exploring_us_refinery_imports/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/exploring_us_refinery_imports/</guid>
      <description>In March, Reuters reported that Saudi Arabia would be reducing it’s March exports of oil to the U.S. by 300,000 barrels per day (bpd).
In 2009, according to the U.S. Energy Information Administration, 39 refineries imported 973,704 bpd of oil from Saudi Arabia - accounting for 10% of US imports.
However in 2016, 18 refineries imported 1,033,890 bpd from Saudi Arabia - accounting for 13% of US imports.
From 2009-2016, 58 U.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>